Break the story. Break the silence.
Spotlight is a drama, history film directed by Tom McCarthy.
The true story of how the Boston Globe uncovered the massive scandal of child molestation and cover-up
within the local Catholic Archdiocese, shaking the entire Catholic Church to its core.
Michael Rezendes, played by Mark Ruffalo.
Walter 'Robby' Robinson, played by Michael Keaton.
Sacha Pfeiffer, played by Rachel McAdams.
Marty Baron, played by Liev Schreiber.
Ben Bradlee, Jr., played by John Slattery.
Matt Carroll, played by Brian d'Arcy James.
Spotlight is a 2015 American biographical drama film directed by Tom
McCarthy and written by McCarthy and Josh Singer.
The film follows The Boston Globe's "Spotlight" team, the oldest continuously operating newspaper investigative journalist unit in the United States, and its
investigation into a decades-long coverup of widespread and systemic child sex abuse by numerous priests of the Roman Catholic Archdiocese of Boston.
Although the plot was original, it is based on a series of stories by the Spotlight
team that earned The Globe the 2003 Pulitzer Prize for Public Service.
The film features an ensemble cast including Mark Ruffalo, Michael Keaton, Rachel McAdams, John
Slattery, Stanley Tucci, Brian d'Arcy James, Liev Schreiber, and Billy Crudup.
Spotlight was shown in the Out of Competition section of the 72nd Venice International Film Festival, the Telluride
Film Festival and the Special Presentations section of the 2015 Toronto International Film Festival.
It was released on November 6, 2015, by Open Road
Films and grossed $98 million worldwide.
It received widespread critical praise, with critics lauding the performances of the cast, historical accuracy, and screenplay; it won
numerous guilds' and critics' association awards, and was named one of the best films of 2015 by various publications.
Spotlight won the Academy Award for Best Picture, along with Best Original Screenplay, from six total nominations,
making it the first Best Picture winner since The Greatest Show on Earth (1952) to win only one other Oscar.
The film also won the Screen Actors Guild Award for
Outstanding Performance by a Cast in a Motion Picture.
The film explores themes of pedophilia, florida,
newspaper, journalist, child abuse.
The tone is emotional and intense.